[{"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caf1", "question": "What is a community of ants called?", "answer": "A colony", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60062a58c9d816e292245c17", "question": "What is Judy Chicago's most well-known work?", "answer": "Regarded as the first epic feminist artwork, \"The Dinner Party\" functions as a symbolic history of women in Western civilization.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a9", "question": "Who voices the character of scientist and inventor Professor John I.Q. Nerdelbaum Frink Jr. on \"The Simpsons\"?", "answer": "Hank Azaria", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a20", "question": "Who portrayed Michael Corleone's second wife in \"The Godfather\"?", "answer": "Diane Keaton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b36ee91c3f17ccc40c8e0b", "question": "What is Dr. Malcolm Crowe\u2019s profession in the film \"The Sixth Sense\"?", "answer": "Child psychologist", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4f7", "question": "What is the street address of the White House?", "answer": "1600 Pennsylvania Avenue", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396d8", "question": "What movie stopped production for a year so Tom Hanks can grow out his hair and lose 50 pounds?", "answer": "Cast Away", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4ae449076251badbeabd", "question": "Who earned the nickname \"Moses\" in the Underground Railroad?", "answer": "Harriet Tubman -- One of the most well-known coordinators of the Underground Railroad, she helped more than 70 slaves to freedom.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339622", "question": "Leonardo DiCaprio played which Shakespearian character in a 1996 movie?", "answer": "Romeo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff51383ff04d658268c92dc", "question": "Which war was ended by the 1763 Treaty of Paris?", "answer": "The signing of the treaty formally ended the Seven Years' War, also known as the French and Indian War.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133980a", "question": "What opera star sang with John Denver on the album \"Perhaps Love\"?", "answer": "Placido Domingo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0fe", "question": "In what country was Adolf Hitler born?", "answer": "Austria", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0b3", "question": "\"He's In Town\" was a hit in 1964 for which British group?", "answer": "The Rockin' Berries", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59f9b85d364247bf200fb87f", "question": "By what chemical process do plants manufacture food?", "answer": "Photosynthesis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab15", "question": "What US state includes the telephone area code 515?", "answer": "Iowa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d76", "question": "What beer-centric movie begins with the MGM lion belching rather than roaring?", "answer": "Strange Brew", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd6a1266c0f9723ab15cb37", "question": "How much time passed between the invention of cans and can openers?", "answer": "48 years", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a831", "question": "The powerful Inca empire had its capital seat at Cuzco in what modern-day South American country?", "answer": "Peru", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe65860ae7e414034b5aeee", "question": "Who was Odette Sansom in World War II?", "answer": "Female British spy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fffa5cb73838c5c8a417f2b", "question": "A quahog is what kind of sea creature?", "answer": "Clam (It is common along the Eastern coast of the American continent, from Prince Edward Island down to the Yucatan Peninsula.)", "category": "science"}, {"id": "601b4b0a49076251badbeac0", "question": "What was Dwight D. Eisenhower's major campaign slogan during the 1952 presidential election?", "answer": "\"I like Ike\" -- Ike was Eisenhower's nickname.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a202", "question": "Diane Belmont was the stage name of which famous actress?", "answer": "Lucille Ball", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393a7", "question": "In the movie \"Live And Let Die\", what ability does Solitaire lose after sleeping with Bond?", "answer": "Her psychic ability", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600241d94be4723ccac2217e", "question": "In the book \"The Hunt for Red October,\" how is the Soviet submarine V. K. Konovalov destroyed?", "answer": "Reactor meltdown", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59067f21ff9c0647b50a8081", "question": "How many gold medals did US swimmer Michael Phelps win at the 2016 Summer Olympics?", "answer": "5", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5e72c93ad0874f1a5e2d1c1d", "question": "How many shower curtain rings does the typical shower curtain have?", "answer": "12", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af4d", "question": "What type of device was the first Sony-branded product, released in 1955?", "answer": "Transistor Radio", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6cd", "question": "Jaundice tends to turn one's skin, and sometimes the whites of the eyes, what color?", "answer": "Yellow", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ab", "question": "Who does Emma Watson play in the Harry Potter films?", "answer": "Hermione", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9f0", "question": "What company makes the Xbox console?", "answer": "Microsoft", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdbc", "question": "What is traditionally the main fruit ingredient in tepenade?", "answer": "Olives", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3dc", "question": "In what period of the Mesozoic era did dinosaurs first appear?", "answer": "Triassic", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fecdd3eec223966ae8f8902", "question": "Who is the godmother of Kurt Cobain and Courtney Love's kid Francis Bean?", "answer": "Drew Barrymore", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5909d339bb53d1af65886510", "question": "On what date did the TV special \"A Charlie Brown Christmas\" made its debut on CBS?", "answer": "December 9, 1965", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a9e96917ccba3ffe45786ef", "question": "Galt MacDermot wrote the music for what 1967 musical?", "answer": "Hair", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b3589ac5db0d66a186cb54d", "question": "Until 1989, what European country was the world\u2019s second largest exporter of bottled wine?", "answer": "Bulgaria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339909", "question": "What baseball movie features a character nicknamed Nuke LaLoosh?", "answer": "Bull Durham", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c02c", "question": "What does Amoco stand for?", "answer": "American Oil Company", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339296", "question": "What is the most common swear word used in the TV series \"Battlestar Galactica\"?", "answer": "Frak", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133974d", "question": "What is Alecia Moore better known as?", "answer": "P!NK", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa05", "question": "Which mountain range lies in the north of Spain, west of The Pyrenees?", "answer": "The Cantabrian Mountains", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb15", "question": "What city was home to the NBA's Jazz before moving to Utah?", "answer": "New Orleans", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febac047e83c707845b20ea", "question": "What was the name of the last known Pinta Island tortoise?", "answer": "Lonesome George", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a180", "question": "In the cartoon \"Wacky Races\" who drove the Turbo Terrific?", "answer": "Peter Perfect", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394d4", "question": "What TV sitcom's final episode revealed that the previous seasons had all been a dream?", "answer": "Newhart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0ae", "question": "Along with Karl Marx, who penned \"The Communist Manifesto\" in 1848?", "answer": "Friedrich Engels", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa7a", "question": "What is the capital of Bhutan?", "answer": "Thimphu", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b61", "question": "What Paul Newman film spawned the hit song \"Raindrops Keep Fallin' on My Head\"?", "answer": "Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8b1f201dd7bf43be5e797", "question": "What does it mean to \"86\" something?", "answer": "Get rid of it", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b445", "question": "How old was Joseph Merrick, also known as Elephant Man, when he died in 1890?", "answer": "27", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339288", "question": "In the movie \"The Hunger Games\", what is Thresh's weapon of choice?", "answer": "A Scimitar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c637", "question": "What name is given to the shellfish that cling to the bottom of ships?", "answer": "Barnacles", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea3a9cff048f679a45ab2c", "question": "What color has the longest wavelength in the visible spectrum?", "answer": "Red", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b8", "question": "Which novel is the movie \"Blade Runner\" loosely based on?", "answer": "Do Androids Dream of Electric Sheep?", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abaa", "question": "What is the state capital of New York?", "answer": "Albany", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad57", "question": "Queen Mary of England made her reputation by trying to rid her country of what segment of the population?", "answer": "Protestants", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133beac", "question": "Tiffany and Co. has a registered trademark on its signature shade of what color?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdab48c0b8cce1e6fda7048", "question": "What is the main ingredient in falafel?", "answer": "Chickpeas", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefbeb76ce05a3942286ef5", "question": "What famous singer was nicknamed \"Chairman of the Board\"?", "answer": "Frank Sinatra", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396da", "question": "What kind of wine does Hannibal Lecter recommend while enjoying a human liver?", "answer": "Chianti", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b114", "question": "What Spanish explorer became the first governor of Puerto Rico in 1508?", "answer": "Juan Ponce de Leon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6ef", "question": "How many squares are there on a standard Scrabble board?", "answer": "225", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d6e", "question": "At what movie's climax does Mookie throw a garbage can through the front window of Sal's Pizzeria?", "answer": "Do the Right Thing's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a44", "question": "What dance craze inspired the 1990 film \"The Forbidden Dance\"?", "answer": "The lambada", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388eb", "question": "What is the dot in the \"i\" called?", "answer": "A tittle", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff5169eff04d658268c92f1", "question": "What activist organized the \"March of the Mill Children\" from Philadelphia to President Teddy Roosevelt's summer home in 1903?", "answer": "Mary Harris Jones -- She organized the march to demand an end to child labour.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7c6cb877e98cb977789c0", "question": "The Great Pyramid of Cholula is located in what country?", "answer": "Mexico", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cef", "question": "Jacob and Wilhelm were the first names of what literary brothers?", "answer": "The Brothers Grimm", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a67", "question": "Who wrote the children's book \"The Trumpet of the Swan\"?", "answer": "E.B. White", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133948c", "question": "In the movie \"Days of Thunder\", what car is Cole told to hit in his first race?", "answer": "The pace car", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c7e", "question": "Which four actresses portray the housewives in the TV show \"Desperate Housewives\"?", "answer": "Teri Hatcher, Eva Longoria, Felicity Huffman and Marcia Cross", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a9e95c97ccba3ffe45786e4", "question": "What alcohol do you mix with lemonade to make a Snowball cocktail?", "answer": "Advocaat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c04", "question": "What novel portrays the life of the Joad family during the Great Depression?", "answer": "The Grapes of Wrath", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fecc1e6ec223966ae8f886f", "question": "Who allegedly wrote the song \"Golden Years\" for Elvis Presley but ended up recording it himself?", "answer": "David Bowie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399a3", "question": "What song off of their \"Joshua Tree\" album was the band U2\u2019s first #1 hit on the US charts?", "answer": "With or Without You", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff144a6b0ee8c595b6d39b6", "question": "What is the name of the first \"Sherlock Holmes\" novel?", "answer": "\"A Study in Scarlet\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fde4cbfc6c6b019850c9a7e", "question": "What Indian Prime Minister guided India through its early years of independence after 1947?", "answer": "Jawaharlal Nehru", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59e6bc59fb6c85e9e634ff5c", "question": "Who sang \"All I Wanna Do\"?", "answer": "Sheryl Crow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff0b1b0e662d71a53650fd2", "question": "Where was the graveyard located where Lord Voldemort made his return?", "answer": "Little Hangleton", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea77bfff048f679a45abce", "question": "Meningitis is characterized by what major symptoms?", "answer": "Stiff neck, sudden high fever and a severe headache", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c965", "question": "Aviatophobia is a fear of what?", "answer": "Flying", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9dc", "question": "Which fruit can restore your health in Donkey Kong 64?", "answer": "Watermelon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bafc", "question": "The clarinet is a member of what family of instruments?", "answer": "Woodwinds", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac5e", "question": "Who is said to have been presented to Julius Caesar in a carpet?", "answer": "Cleopatra", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e35", "question": "Who is Campbell Scott's mother?", "answer": "Colleen Dewhurst", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c03f", "question": "Where is Sclerotinite found?", "answer": "Coal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c09d", "question": "What wine barrel contains 252 gallons?", "answer": "Tun", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2d9", "question": "Arthur Jefferson better known as who?", "answer": "Stan Laurel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fb6", "question": "What comedy show parodied soap operas with \"As the Stomach Turns\"?", "answer": "The Carol Burnett Show", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59f9b9cb364247bf200fb891", "question": "Who is credited with designing the icon look of the Morris Mini-Minor?", "answer": "Alec Issigonis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339587", "question": "What movie earned Steven Spielberg his first Oscar?", "answer": "Schindler's List", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd6a8376c0f9723ab15cb64", "question": "What is the first animal of the Chinese zodiac?", "answer": "Rat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecd1e4ec223966ae8f88c1", "question": "While filming \"Guardians of the Galaxy\", what did director James Gunn give out as rewards to his actors and crew?", "answer": "Play-Doh", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133beff", "question": "Which snooker player ended Stephen Hendry's five-year unbeaten run at The Crucible?", "answer": "Ken Doherty", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcce", "question": "If you give something up for Lent, how many days are you going without?", "answer": "Forty", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a4d9a3208b8581f80b092ba", "question": "Who directed the highly anticipated film \"Blade Runner 2049\"?", "answer": "Denis Villeneuve", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b303", "question": "Who did Brazil name an official national treasure in 1962, so he wouldn't emigrate to Italy?", "answer": "Pele", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bbb", "question": "What Beatles movie features bad guys called Blue Meanies?", "answer": "Yellow Submarine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aee9", "question": "Which royal house consisted of Henry IV, Henry V and Henry VI?", "answer": "House of Lancaster", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58dba39f874c93a3298b213e", "question": "Who was nicknamed La Pucelle d'Orl\u00e9ans?", "answer": "Joan of Arc", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef631a6ce05a3942286e62", "question": "Who was the first guest on \"Late Night with David Letterman\"?", "answer": "Bill Murray", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae90", "question": "Which US president resided at the Hermitage, a plantation in Tennessee?", "answer": "Andrew Jackson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390fa", "question": "Who wrote the 1991 novel \"The Deceiver\"?", "answer": "Frederick Forsyth", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b212", "question": "Who was assassinated by Dan White?", "answer": "Harvey Milk and George Moscone", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1b6", "question": "In the \"Great Upheaval\", three quarters of what people were forcibly removed from Nova Scotia?", "answer": "The Acadians", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015e088fe83fe1f2a824b8f", "question": "What was the highest denomination bill ever printed in the United States?", "answer": "$100,000", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b62f", "question": "In the Western Union's alphabet what is the letter \"C\" known as?", "answer": "Chicago", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338880", "question": "What is the last word in the Bible?", "answer": "Amen", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abba", "question": "What US state is also known as The Golden State?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b571b4e67df192a942e3367", "question": "FINA is the governing body of what sport?", "answer": "Swimming", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339897", "question": "What classic movie starred Vivien Leigh and Scarlett O'Hara?", "answer": "Gone With the Wind", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0c3", "question": "In what year did Martin Luther King Jr. deliver his \"I Have a  Dream\" speech?", "answer": "1963", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f85", "question": "In the nursery rhyme what is Friday's child?", "answer": "Loving and Giving", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fef60656ce05a3942286e4a", "question": "In what sport do you use the terms \"Chicken Salad\" and \"McTwist\"?", "answer": "Snowboarding", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac5f", "question": "Who was the father of Cleopatra's twins?", "answer": "Mark Antony", "category": "history"}, {"id": "596761082b59efe0e9417ea0", "question": "The fear of some unknown evil is called what?", "answer": "Panphobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9b0", "question": "If you were infected with the variola virus, what disease did you have?", "answer": "Smallpox", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b5e", "question": "How many lines are in a limerick?", "answer": "5", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7ce", "question": "A benzene ring is made up of atoms of what element?", "answer": "Carbon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a2f", "question": "What 1984 song by Prince was his first to hit #1 on the Billboard charts?", "answer": "When Doves Cry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133963f", "question": "In which country was Greta Garbo born?", "answer": "Sweden", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa56cec73aa70ea0b70b2d", "question": "Which two towns were destroyed and buried when Mount Vesuvius erupted in 79 A.D.?", "answer": "Pompeii and Herculaneum were both destroyed by the eruption in 79 A.D.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c100", "question": "What three letter word stands for a small opening and a clothing company?", "answer": "Gap", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9da", "question": "How many dots are on a Pac-Man board?", "answer": "240", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bf2", "question": "What year did actor Heath Ledger die?", "answer": "2008", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f77", "question": "Which American author wrote \"Moby Dick\"?", "answer": "Herman Melville", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5937ea5908d98002fdd633a1", "question": "What is the largest body of fresh water in the world by surface area?", "answer": "Lake Superior", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1cc", "question": "Creme de Menthe, Creme de Cacao and what other ingredient are combined to make a Grasshopper cocktail?", "answer": "Fresh cream", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ad1", "question": "What name is shared by America's first Naval hero and the bass player for Led Zeppelin?", "answer": "John Paul Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff7c0fa2b316f4693fb679a", "question": "What is a duel between three people called?", "answer": "Truel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339872", "question": "In Disney's \"Alice in Wonderland\", what does the bottle marked \"Drink Me\" do?", "answer": "Shrinks you", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1ee", "question": "Ian Brown fronts which English band?", "answer": "The Stone Roses", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febb8557e83c707845b2133", "question": "What is the national bird of the Bahamas?", "answer": "The flamingo", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab21", "question": "What is the capital of Mozambique?", "answer": "Maputo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59523e7e736d4be723796b50", "question": "What are the names of the \"Trailer Park Boys\"?", "answer": "Ricky, Julian and Bubbles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cf4", "question": "Whose painting entitled \"Impression: Sunrise\" gave the name to the Impressionist movement?", "answer": "Monet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5f95b02755722f97b22684db", "question": "What does Dumbledore give to Ron in his will?", "answer": "Deluminator", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b323514bf195a31e15d73ab", "question": "Sergey Bubka has set a world record in which field event over 30 times?", "answer": "Pole Vault", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3f9", "question": "What year did James Garfield start his presidency?", "answer": "1881", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f9f", "question": "What movie begins with a feather coming to rest in front of a Savannah, Georgia, bus stop?", "answer": "Forrest Gump", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7d1", "question": "What distance did the Romans once define as a thousand paces?", "answer": "A mile", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8a4", "question": "Which element of the periodic table is named for the inventor of the cyclotron?", "answer": "Lawrencium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7ca0e877e98cb97778a01", "question": "In which district of the United Kingdom is Scaffel Pike, England's highest peak, found?", "answer": "The Lake District", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca77", "question": "An imperial fathom has how many yards?", "answer": "2", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133981d", "question": "Who provided the voice for Mister Swackhammer, the main antagonist in the movie Space Jam?", "answer": "Danny DeVito", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58d06d10870e6f05ba600856", "question": "What 16th century physician is often credited for revolutionized anatomy by performing dissections?", "answer": "Andreas Vesalius", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339685", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", who normally drives Springfield Elementary's school bus?", "answer": "Otto", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b76c", "question": "How many points is the outer white ring of an Olympic archery target worth?", "answer": "One", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffa5611c73aa70ea0b70b27", "question": "In which country is May Day the only holiday workers are obliged to be given the day off yet still be paid for it?", "answer": "France", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a224", "question": "Who produced a hit song with \"I'll Be Missing You\" in 1997?", "answer": "Puff Daddy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4ddff06d333868d34d70c", "question": "What was the family name of Mary Queen of Scots?", "answer": "Stuart", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2a9", "question": "How did actor Humphrey Bogart die?", "answer": "Esophageal cancer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b0e8ab964118b2bb3809c6", "question": "Which artist released an album titled \"St. Valentine\u2019s Day\" in 1948?", "answer": "Bing Crosby", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe768aaeec85e375820b2a4", "question": "What country once had a banknote that featured a woman riding a shark?", "answer": "Cook Islands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0e5", "question": "Who directed the film \"Serpico\"?", "answer": "Sidney Lumet", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600cc0c66de0eb824d4052db", "question": "In which mountain range can you find Australia\u2019s tallest peak?", "answer": "Australian Alps -- It is covered in ski resorts and in the summer, many people hike to its tallest peak, Mount Kosciuszko.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca32", "question": "What is a group of lions called?", "answer": "Pride", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fef5ee66ce05a3942286e3b", "question": "Kyle Korver is frequently mistaken for which famous actor?", "answer": "Ashton Kutcher", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c21", "question": "Sting was the lead singer of which popular band?", "answer": "The Police", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b990", "question": "Which NBA team plays its home games at the Barclays Centre?", "answer": "Brooklyn Nets", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393c6", "question": "What Hollywood director had a small role in the movie \"The Blues Brothers\"?", "answer": "Steven Spielberg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afef", "question": "President William McKinley was a member of what political party?", "answer": "Republican Party", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5aa", "question": "When was the Guinness beer brand first introduced?", "answer": "1759", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a15b", "question": "The Golden Lion is awarded at which film festival?", "answer": "Venice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133907c", "question": "Which writers works include \"The Dark Eyes of London\", \"Four Just Men\" and \"Sanders of the River\"?", "answer": "Edgar Wallace", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c89", "question": "What country was the setting for both Rudyard Kipling\u2019s \"The Jungle Book\" and \"Gunga Din\"?", "answer": "India", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ab99daa21a8909e5c332d42", "question": "What was the original working title of the movie \"Help!\", starring the Beatles?", "answer": "Eight Arms To Hold You", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe5225e1bf59ab7d2e380e7", "question": "What is the soft, triangular, fleshy part of the inside of a horse's hoof called?", "answer": "Frog", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febb5057e83c707845b211e", "question": "What is Mars' atmosphere mostly made of?", "answer": "Carbon dioxide", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c15a", "question": "What does Karaoke literally mean?", "answer": "Empty Orchestra", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c61a", "question": "What is the chemical symbol for Silver?", "answer": "Ag", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdbe", "question": "What is traditionally the main fruit ingredient in a rickey?", "answer": "Limes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3df", "question": "Which is the only Portuguese-speaking Latin American country?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b79f", "question": "What is the dominant fruit flavoring in Southern Comfort?", "answer": "Peach", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fec8af5ec223966ae8f8835", "question": "In what book of the Bible did the prison warden find Andy's rock hammer in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Exodus", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b13c", "question": "In what year did Joseph Smith first organize the Mormon Church?", "answer": "1830", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba00", "question": "What sport did hall-of-famer Honus Wagner play?", "answer": "Baseball", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe65e461f3c0ead6880d628", "question": "What biblical figure had a slave named Onesimus?", "answer": "Philemon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398b6", "question": "What movie stars Marlon Brando as a boxer who stands up against a corrupt union?", "answer": "On the Waterfront", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388c0", "question": "What category of writing are the Hugo and Nebula awards given for?", "answer": "Science Fiction", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a432", "question": "In what country would you most likely encounter a Tasmanian devil?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff515beff04d658268c92ec", "question": "What queen led a famous revolt against the Roman Empire?", "answer": "Zenobia, queen of the Palmyrene Empire, expanded the empire, by conquering Egypt and expelling the Roman prefect, Tenagino Probus.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1d8", "question": "White creme de menthe is added to what alcohol to make a Stinger cocktail?", "answer": "Cognac", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a4a94bc61d1b4d384d5d671", "question": "Who is Dana Elaine Owens more commonly known as?", "answer": "Queen Latifah", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396f1", "question": "What Stanley Kubrick movie featured gangs of young punks loose in a future Britain?", "answer": "A Clockwork Orange", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b321", "question": "Who was the last Nascar driver to serve jail time for running moonshine?", "answer": "Buddy Arrington", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339472", "question": "Who plays the role of Franz Liebkind in the 2005 movie \"The Producers\"?", "answer": "Will Ferrell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abb3", "question": "What airport has the code MME?", "answer": "Durham Tees Valley", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffb68a05dad637d903c8843", "question": "Which of Sri Lanka\u2019s official languages also has official status in Singapore and parts of\u202fIndia?", "answer": "Tamil", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339375", "question": "In the movie \"Cast Away\", how long was Chuck Nolan marooned on the island?", "answer": "4 years", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a8e", "question": "What was the name of Paul McCartney's backup group from 1971 to 1981?", "answer": "Wings", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339741", "question": "Peter Marshall was the host of what game show for 15 years?", "answer": "The Hollywood Squares", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b658", "question": "What baseball great was nicknamed the Iron Man?", "answer": "Cal Ripken Jr.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b7", "question": "From which movie did the phrase \"You can't handle the truth!\" originate?", "answer": "A Few Good Men", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a90c", "question": "What major river runs through Florence?", "answer": "Arno", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ba", "question": "In Shakespeare's \"Romeo and Julie\", what is Romeo's surname?", "answer": "Montague", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5e8a67c89a45431f553a9cd2", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Great Expectations\"?", "answer": "Charles Dickens", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad67", "question": "The original Teamsters union was formed to protect who?", "answer": "Horse carriage drivers", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b4bd849076251badbeac9", "question": "What country's declaration of war triggered the start of World War I?", "answer": "After Bosnian Serb Gavrilo Princip assassinated Archduke Franz Ferdinand, Austria-Hungary declared war on Serbia in July 1914.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8ae", "question": "What number of Downing Street serves as the residence for the Prime Minister of the UK?", "answer": "10", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59220535a4edfd43a087ade8", "question": "How high is the center of the tennis court net?", "answer": "3 feet, or 91 centimetres", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5bbc950a60f0007efaba0e5f", "question": "In Telltale's Season 1 of the \"The Walking Dead\" game series, what is the name of the main character?", "answer": "Lee", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefc5546ce05a3942286f3b", "question": "What is a pli\u00e9 in ballet?", "answer": "Bending at the knees", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a07", "question": "Who was the lead singer of the band Audioslave?", "answer": "Chris Cornell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59f9b943364247bf200fb88a", "question": "Who popularized the song \"A Boy Named Sue\" in 1969?", "answer": "Johnny Cash", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd66d2ba5bfecdd737e089c", "question": "Who is the only person to be named \"TIME\" magazine's Person of the Year three times?", "answer": "Franklin D. Roosevelt", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c422", "question": "What birds do Chinese and Japanese fisherman commonly use?", "answer": "Cormorants", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6f8", "question": "Which state is home to the Fort Apache Indian Reservation?", "answer": "Arizona", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5f9f4335af848b908361b870", "question": "Which is the largest city in Africa?", "answer": "Cairo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59ded2caea2747c8aff16d42", "question": "What line on a weather map links all points of equal pressure?", "answer": "Isobar", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b139", "question": "What country's population hit the one billion mark in May 2000?", "answer": "India", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febab647e83c707845b20e8", "question": "Which planet has moons named Hippocamp and Proteus?", "answer": "Neptune", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a33c", "question": "Lock, Shock and Barrel were characters in which Halloween film?", "answer": "The Nightmare Before Christmas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7d01a877e98cb97778a5b", "question": "Nova Scotia is Latin for what?", "answer": "New Scotland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59da1baef6756c9b30ba14fc", "question": "Kiev is the capital of which European country?", "answer": "Ukraine", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff3c2084f032c0db195b47d", "question": "Who was the first wife of King Henry VIII?", "answer": "Catherine of Aragon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a116", "question": "Who recorded the album \"Wings Over America\" in 1976?", "answer": "Paul McCartney and Wings", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b666", "question": "In the game of 9-ball, the pool balls are initially placed in a grouping of what shape?", "answer": "Diamond", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd2d3a32596a59cbdfbd39c", "question": "What skyrocketed Apple to fame in 1984?", "answer": "A Superbowl ad", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6f4", "question": "How many sides does a trapezoid have?", "answer": "4", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0da", "question": "In 1995, who became the first Republican Speaker of the House in 40 years?", "answer": "Newt Gingrich", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a00c", "question": "What two Orlando Magic teammates made their screen debuts in \"Blue Chips\"?", "answer": "Shaquille O'Neal and Anfernee Hardaway", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b83e", "question": "What 2 articles of clothing are tokens in the standard Monopoly game?", "answer": "Shoe and Top Hat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d34", "question": "Who's responsible for performing \"The Ballad of John and Yoko\"?", "answer": "The Beatles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac33", "question": "Which side did Britain support in the US Civil War?", "answer": "The Confederacy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a4d99ea08b8581f80b092b8", "question": "What month in 2017 did the United Kingdom begin Brexit Negotiations?", "answer": "March", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59071b803745b36be73039c2", "question": "Which company publishes the Chew comics series?", "answer": "Image Comics", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b62", "question": "What broadcast television network debuted on October 9, 1986?", "answer": "FOX", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8c5", "question": "What desert is home to the Ahaggar and Tibesti mountains?", "answer": "Sahara", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c84b", "question": "In what organ of the human body would you find the malleus?", "answer": "The ear", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d07", "question": "Whose sidekick was named Garth Algar?", "answer": "Wayne Campbell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab960b86faa38a764be51b", "question": "What former republic did the Trabant originate from?", "answer": "East Germany, or German Democratic Republic", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a16", "question": "What is Bridget Jones' home city?", "answer": "London", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339649", "question": "Who is worshiped in the \"Temple of Doom\" discovered by Indiana Jones?", "answer": "Kali", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff7bd562b316f4693fb678d", "question": "In the 1980s, how did American Airlines famously save $40,000?", "answer": "By removing a single olive from each salad served on American Airlines flights", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd7c", "question": "What is the French name for a restaurant wine steward?", "answer": "Sommelier", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac15", "question": "The Union of the Comoros is located on the northern end of which water channel?", "answer": "Mozambique Channel", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339893", "question": "What was Lucy and Ricky's last name on the TV series \"I Love Lucy\"?", "answer": "Ricardo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c4a", "question": "According to poet Carl Sandburg, what \"creeps in on little cat feet\"?", "answer": "The fog", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b15c", "question": "Who was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize in 1979?", "answer": "Mother Teresa", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad0e", "question": "Attila the Hun was the leader of which ancient empire?", "answer": "The Hunnic Empire", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1c3", "question": "Which politician was given the nickname Tarzan?", "answer": "Michael Heseltine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a073", "question": "In the film \"Saving Private Ryan\" what was Private Ryan's first name?", "answer": "James", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febbaef7e83c707845b2147", "question": "Which character in the \"Street Fighter\" series was inspired by martial-arts legend Bruce Lee?", "answer": "Fei Long", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4ba949076251badbeac6", "question": "The first North American\u00a0English seasonal camp was founded where?", "answer": "St. John's, Newfoundland -- In 1583, Sir\u00a0Humphrey Gilbert, by the\u00a0royal prerogative\u00a0of\u00a0Queen Elizabeth I, founded\u00a0St. John's.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fecd193ec223966ae8f88c0", "question": "What was Joan Crawford's last film?", "answer": "\"Trog\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6018bbd2d96d05b23b28164f", "question": "What event prompted the first New Year\u2019s Eve ball drop in Times Square?", "answer": "New York Times paper owner Adolph Ochs hired a metal worker to build the ball-drop due to a fireworks ban in the city.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a036", "question": "In the show \"Family Guy\", what does Quagmire do in an attempt to get out of his marriage?", "answer": "Fake his own death", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5909cf7abb53d1af658864f4", "question": "In the film \"Home Alone 2\", what city was the McCallister family planning on vacationing in?", "answer": "Miami", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a35a", "question": "What is the most sacred river of India?", "answer": "The Ganges", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe12e58e39efa6330e0fed2", "question": "Which US state has the most lighthouses?", "answer": "Michigan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5e4", "question": "What was known as \"the gun that won the West\"?", "answer": "The Winchester Rifle", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a57", "question": "The 2006 Mel Gibson movie \"Apocalypto\" concerns the demise of what ancient empire?", "answer": "The Mayan Empire", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d38", "question": "Who's responsible for \"The Ballad of Cable Hogue\"?", "answer": "Sam Peckinpah", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c915", "question": "Which element has the atomic number of 12?", "answer": "Magnesium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59049988cf93664eb1048691", "question": "Which famous actor is honored with a statue in Leicester Square?", "answer": "Charlie Chaplin", "category": "geography"}]